lumoslearning.com 2019-05-08

# Privacy Policy | Lumos Learning

**IMPORTANT:

THIS PAGE PROVIDES GENERAL INFORMATION ABOUT THE PRIVACY POLICY OF THIS WEBSITE. IF YOU ARE UNDER 18 YEARS OF AGE, PLEASE BE SURE TO READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY WITH YOUR PARENTS OR GUARDIAN AND ASK QUESTIONS ABOUT THINGS YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND.

**

www.lumoslearning.com (herein referred to as Website) is owned, managed and operated by Lumos Information Services (dba Lumos Learning) (hereinafter referred to as Company or We or Us or Our) a Limited Liability Company registered in New Jersey, USA with the registered address at PO Box 1575, Piscataway, NJ 08855.

The Privacy Policy (hereinafter referred to as Policy) outlines the Company practices, policies and procedures concerning the collection, use, and protection of information collected from the users of this Website, in whatever capacity they use this Website (herein referred to as User, You or Your). We are committed to protecting your online privacy while you use this Website as a visitor or registered user.

This Policy and Our privacy practices in pursuance thereof are consistent with the relevant provisions contained under Federal Trade Commission Act (15 U.S. Code 41 et seq.) (hereinafter, referred to as Rules).

By using this Website or any features thereof, you understand, acknowledge, and agree to the clause(s) and sub-clause(s) contained hereinafter. In case you do not agree to any of the following clause(s) or sub-clause(s), you understand, acknowledge and agree that your sole remedy against the Company is the cessation of further use of this Website.

 _This Policy is incorporated by reference within Our Terms of Use Agreement and shall be read in conjunction with the said Terms of Use Agreement._

* ### 1\. Personally identifiable Information Collection, Non Collection and Usage:

  * **1.1 Sensitive Personal Data or Information :**

We do not collect any Sensitive Personal Data or Information, from any user of this Website. During the online registration process, We ask for your email id, preferred password in order to allow secure access to the features of the Website that are reserved for the registered members of this Website (hereinafter, referred to as Member Area). Once registered, You can access the Member Area by keying in your login id and the corresponding password.

  * **1.2 Personally identifiable information :**

In order to become a registered member of this Website, You are required to fill and submit an online Registration Form. Through this Registration Form, We collect certain personally identifiable information from You including, but not limited to, Name, email id, login name and password.

We do not collect any other personal information about Users except when such Users specifically provide personal information on a Voluntary basis (for example user name and password, login information) in connection with a request for technical support, whether by email or phone request or when personal information is provided on behalf of an individual (for example, by a school administrator or teacher entering identifying information about teachers, students or parents or library for the purpose of setting up users). Personally identifiable information may also be collected from website users in the process of search queries and other support activities and may include but not limited to log-in information, IP address, device information, credit card information, debit card information, PayPal via stripe etc. as the case may be

Based on the Online programs enrolled by the User, the personal information provided may also consist of, but limited to (i) school administrators’ names, contact information and Login Information, (ii) teachers’ names, Department of Education identification number, contact information and Login Information, (iii) identifying information about students provided by the school administrator or teacher (e.g. students’ names or school-issued identification numbers) or parents, solely for the purpose of tracking and gathering data regarding such students’ use of various products, and (iv) parents’ names and contact information provided by the parent themselves or school administrator or teacher, solely for reference.

    * **1.2.1 Personal Information provided on behalf of children :**

We understand that Users who are under 13 years of age (“Children”) need special safeguards and privacy protection, and it is the intent of Lumos Information Services to fully comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”). Lumos Information Services does not collect personal information directly from Children online at any point. Lumos Information Services only receives personal information about Children directly from school administrators and/or teachers or Parents when they set up Student account. Parents or legal guardians should contact their Child’s school to review any personal information regarding their Children that the school’s administrators or teachers have provided to Lumos Information Services.

Parents or legal guardians can request that their Children’s school not provide any personal information through Student account to Lumos Information Services. Please be aware that, depending on the school’s policies, if a parent or legal guardian makes such a request, their Children may no longer be eligible to be enrolled in Lumos Information Services programs. Therefore, such a request by a parent or legal guardian could potentially terminate their Children’s participation in and their use of Lumos Information Services programs.

As a parent or guardian, by purchasing the program you agree that you are providing the approval to your child to use the Lumos Learning online program 

  * **1.3 Collection of Personally Identifiable Information:**

Besides the Registration Form, We may collect the aforementioned personally identifiable information, or any part thereof, from the Survey Forms, Referral Forms, Newsletters Subscription Forms, Invitation Forms, Sweepstakes/Competitions/Contests Forms, or any other promotional or research activities undertaken by the Company and which necessitate the collection of such personally identifiable information.

We collect information about the people, and groups you are connected to and are a part of your contacts list. We also collect contact information if you choose to upload, sync or import it from a device (such as an address book or call log or SMS log history), which we use for things like helping you and others find people you may know and connect with them and share the product information, if you wish to

* ### 2\. Use of Personally identifiable information:

  * 2.1 The aforementioned personally identifiable information is collected in order to achieve the basic objectives of the Website and to provide You with timely, efficient, and personalized services (wherever required).

  * 2.2 Your email ID is used firstly to verify the genuineness of Your registration application, and then to activate Your account with the Website, and finally to communicate with You regarding latest updates and news of the Website, respond to Your requests, and other important information that You may require either to act upon or for Your general information purposes.

  * 2.3 We only send newsletters, latest offers, news, and updates to subscribers who opt to receive the newsletter. If You do not want Us to contact You for this purpose, You can opt-out by clicking the Unsubscribe link that is included in all Our similar emails.

  * 2.4 We may send certain communications to Your postal address, which are required by law to be communicated via offline mode as well.

  * 2.5 We allow the option to share certain website details on social media like Facebook, twitter, LinkedIn or Google plus in order to help You share and stay connected with Your network of friends on these popular media.

  * 2.6 As a registered member of this Website, You are also provided with the facility to post blogs on the Website, which are publicly accessible to all visitors to this Website. While We reserve the right to moderate all such blog posts for compliance with Our Terms of Use Agreement, We shall not be liable for any such blog post that may compromise the poster’s online privacy. Consequently, You may use Your Pet Name or real name within the blog post, but We disclaim any liability arising out of all such disclosures by the user him/ herself.

  * 2.7 In the event you provide a feedback to Our website or leave a testimonial for Us, We shall treat all the personally identifiable information contained in such feedback/testimonial in accordance with the provisions contained herein.

  * 2.8 We ask your email id in case of Forgotten password to reset your password. You are advised to change the password after logging into your id using the temporary password provided as per the suggestion in our mail. In case the account has been created using Username and not email id, we take necessary account details over phone for resetting the password. We treat this a personally identifiable information and is treated in accordance with the provisions contained herein

  * 2.9 Only that much personally identifiable information is collected as is absolutely vital to provide You with efficient and timely services.

  * 2.10 All Your personally identifiable information so collected is kept confidential and never shared with, or sold to, or otherwise commercially traded with, any third party without Your prior express written consent. However, We may share all or part of such personally identifiable information with trusted third party providers and/or suppliers who work on Our behalf in order to provide You with efficient and timely services. However, all such third party providers and/or suppliers are under appropriate burden of confidentiality not to share, disclose, or independently use any of the personally identifiable information so collected.

  * 2.11 The personally identifiable information may be shared wihout consent or notice to meet legal requirements pursuant to applicable law or government request, to detect fraud, to prevent harm to other users or public

* ### 3\. Retention of Personally Identifiable Information:

We reserve the right to retain any and all of Your personally identifiable information so collected through this Website for as long duration as is mandated by the applicable law for the time being in force as as governed by Our administrative expediency, whichever period expires later.

* ### 4\. Review of Personally Identifiable Information:

All the personally identifiable information so collected is available for review and revision in Your Member Area. You can, at any time, review and/or change such personally identifiable information, which is incorrect or inaccurate or has turned obsolete.  
However, You understand, acknowledge and agree that We shall not be liable for the authenticity of any personally identifiable information You provide at any time.

* ### 5\. Non Provision of Personally Identifiable Information:

We collect only reasonable amount of personally identifiable information in order to provide You with efficient and timely services.  
However, should You choose not to provide Us with the requested personally identifiable information, You understand, acknowledge and agree that You don’t have any actionable claim in this regard against the Company and the Company shall not obligated to deliver the requested services in the absence of the provision of the requested personally identifiable information.

* ### 6\. Non Personally identifiable Information – Collection and Usage

  * **6.1 Non Personally identifiable information collection:**

When You visit different pages of this Website, We also collect certain non personally identifiable information including, but not limited to, the type of browser used to access this Website, Internet Protocol (IP) Address of Your computer system, IP address of Your Internet Service Provider (ISP), the operating system installed on Your computer system, etc.

  * **6.2 Usage of Non Personally Identifiable Information:**

We use non personally identifiable information to improve the layout and content of Our Website, provide You with customised advertisements, analyse the Website usage, and enhance Your overall experience of using this Website.

* ### 7\. Cookies Policy :

We use cookies to collect the aforementioned non personally identifiable information from the users of this Website. Cookies are small text files that are placed on the hard drive of Your computer system by a Web page server. The cookies are meant to determine such information as: how You use Our Website, how You use Our services in general, types of data accessed, time and volume of use, duration of sessions and other similar usage. The cookies are also used to avoid repeat login while the session is still open. Our cookies do not, in any way, compromise on Your online privacy or damage Your computer system in any manner whatsoever. However, You shall be solely responsible for regularly clearing cookies, cached data and temporary internet files from Your computer system in order to manage the downloaded data, if any.

* ### 8\. Private Messaging :

Lumos Information Services may offer private messaging to certain registered Users. Users should be aware that any information posted in these forums will be received by the specified User’s account. Lumos Information Services has no obligation to monitor the private messaging system. Lumos Information Services reserves the right, however, at all times to disclose any information as necessary to satisfy any law, regulation or governmental request, or to edit, or remove any information or materials, in whole or in part, that in the sole discretion of Lumos Information Services are objectionable or in violation of this privacy policy or the terms and conditions governing the User’s use of the Website.

* ### 9\. Links :

  * 9.1 Website may contain links to other Web sites, chat rooms, or other resources that Lumos Information Services provides for Users’ convenience (the “Linked Sites”). The Linked Sites are not under the control of Lumos Information Services, and Lumos Information Services is not responsible for the content available on any Linked Site. The Linked Sites do not imply the endorsement of material from Lumos Information Services on any Linked Site, and Lumos Information Services expressly disclaims all liability with regard to Users’ access to such Linked Sites. Access to any Web sites linked to Lumos Information Services is at Users’ own risk.

  * 9.2 At our discretion, we may include or offer Third Party Products or Services on our Website. These Third Party services may have separate and independent Privacy Policies. We , therefore, have no liability or responsibility for the content and activities of these linked sites.

* ### 10\. Copyrights :

The contents of this Website are Copyright © of the Company. Any contents of the Website, including texts, documents, logos, images, graphics, video, their arrangement and adaptation on the same site are subject to the laws of intellectual property and protected by copyright. The copy, alteration, distribution, publication or use of these contents on other sites to trading purposes is not permitted without the specific authorization of Lumos Information Services or the relevant third party that owns such intellectual property right.

* ### 11\. Trademarks :

All the trademarks and logos belong to Lumos Information Services, displayed on the Website are exclusive property of Lumos Information Services. Any use and/ or reproduction of the same for any purposes or by means is expressly prohibited and will be persecuted under the appropriate laws.  
The trademarks & logos belonging to third parties displayed on the Website are the exclusive property of their owners and any use/ or reproduction is prohibited. The third party links and logos used are only for identification and to provide access to their services.

* ### 12\. Commitment to Data Security :

To Prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of Information, Lumos Information Services has put in place commercially reasonable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information Lumos Information Services collects. Lumos Information Services also uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol on registration and login pages to protect personal information.  
For Purchase of products from our Website, we ask for Credit Card number. These transactions are secured using licensed secure server software which encrypts the information you provide.  
Additionally, we periodically review our operations and business practices for compliance with corporate policies and procedures governing the security, confidentiality and quality of our information.

* ### 13\. Your Consent :

By Using our Website, you consent to Our Privacy Policy.

* ### 14\. Changes in Privacy Policy :

We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to amend and update this Policy or any part thereof at any time. We shall notify any major amendment(s) in the Policy by a notice requesting perusal on the homepage, which shall run for fifteen (15) days from such amendment(s). All such amendment(s) and updates shall come into effect immediately upon posting on the Website page. You are, therefore, advised to visit this Website page periodically to remain informed about the latest changes affected to this Policy. Your continued usage of this Website constitutes your implied acceptance of the amended Privacy Policy.

* ### 15.Disputes

**Any dispute or claim relating in any way to your use of any of our services or products, or to any products or services accessed through lumoslearning.com will be resolved by binding arbitration, rather than in court,** except that you may assert claims in small claims court if your claims qualify. The Federal Arbitration Act and federal arbitration law apply to this agreement.

**There is no judge or jury in arbitration, and court review of an arbitration award is limited. However, an arbitrator can award on an individual basis the same damages and relief as a court (including injunctive and declaratory relief or statutory damages), and must follow the terms of these Conditions of Use as a court would.**

To begin an arbitration proceeding, you must send a letter requesting arbitration and describing your claim to our registered agent Corporation Service Company, Spiegel & Utrera. The arbitration will be conducted by the American Arbitration Association (AAA) under its rules, including the AAA’s Supplementary Procedures for Consumer-Related Disputes. The AAA’s rules are available at www.adr.org or by calling 1-800-778-7879. Payment of all filing, administration and arbitrator fees will be governed by the AAA’s rules. Likewise, Licensor will not seek attorneys’ fees and costs in arbitration unless the arbitrator determines the claims are frivolous. You may choose to have the arbitration conducted by telephone, based on written submissions, or in person in the county where you live or at another mutually agreed location.

**We each agree that any dispute resolution proceedings will be conducted only on an individual basis and not in a class, consolidated or representative action.** If for any reason a claim proceeds in court rather than in arbitration **we each waive any right to a jury trial.** We also both agree that you or we may bring suit in court to enjoin infringement or other misuse of intellectual property rights.

* ### 16\. Applicable Law

By using any of our Service or Product, you agree that the Federal Arbitration Act, applicable federal law, and the laws of the state of New Jersey, without regard to principles of conflict of laws, will govern these Conditions of Use and any dispute of any sort that might arise without giving effect to any Conflict of Laws provisions. We do not claim that this Website or the services offered on or through this Website are appropriate, legal or available for use in other locations. Accordingly, Your use of this Website is at Your own sole risk. You assume all knowledge of the applicable law and shall be responsible for compliance with any such law(s).

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of our websites, or your dealings with this web site, please contact us at:  
Company: Lumos Information Services  
Phone: 888-309-8227  
Fax: (866)283-6471  
Email: support@lumoslearning.com
